<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tommie Introna: Sound Specialist, Creative Technologist &amp; Researcher</title>
    <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tommie Introna: Sound Specialist, Creative Technologist &amp; Researcher</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 09:21:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Image Test Post</title>
      <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/image-test-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 09:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/image-test-post/</guid>
      <description>This is a test to see how images look! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on the lamenting voice</title>
      <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/reflection-on-the-lamenting-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 18:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/reflection-on-the-lamenting-voice/</guid>
      <description>Recently I watched a talk by Eleni Ikoniadou in which she presented her recent work Future Chrous. https://schedule.mozillafestival.org/session/QTHPSU-1
She discussed how in western thinking, speech is often taken as a marker of human inteligence. For Aristottle via Heidegger - man is a political speaking animal, a being who has a language which addresses and discusses its world. For the Greeks, voice without speech was considered irrational and dangerous associated with female, animal, disabled and non-human entities</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November Research Summary</title>
      <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/november-research-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 12:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/november-research-summary/</guid>
      <description>In 1997, artist and music producer Terre Thaemlitz released her album Die Roboter under the moniker Rubato. The album comprises piano interpretations of classic Kraftwerk titles. On first listen, the piano rendition sounds like a live performance by a talented and expressive pianist, playing a real piano with rich acoustic tones. The only sonic hint of manipulation is the noise that washes over the piano playing.
LISTEN: Die Roboter Rubato: Piano interpretations of Kraftwerk titles by Terre Thaemlitz</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a sound artist, creative technologist, and educator working with sound using technology. I co-founded Black Shuck Co-operative, which produces moving image, audio and digital projects. I also work with young people in various settings, producing artworks and delivering training. I am completing an MRes Creative Computing course at the University of the Arts London (2022-2023).
Work with me! With over 10 years of experience working in art, technology and education, I&amp;rsquo;ve done a bit of everything and am open to new opportunities to collaborate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
