<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>portfolio on Tommie Introna: Sound Specialist, Creative Technologist &amp; Researcher</title>
    <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/tags/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in portfolio on Tommie Introna: Sound Specialist, Creative Technologist &amp; Researcher</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/tags/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Womb of things to be and tomb of things that were</title>
      <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/womb-of-things-to-be-and-tomb-of-things-that-were/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/womb-of-things-to-be-and-tomb-of-things-that-were/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Womb of things to be and tomb of things that were&amp;rsquo; is a film by Charles Pryor and Marleen Boschen that explores collaborative survival, containment and vulnerability through seeds. Via episodic, speculative storytelling we follow seed banking and saving practices across the globe from the Millennium Seed Bank and the John Innes Centre in the UK, to a forest gene bank in Poland and a food sovereignty organisation in Palestine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water Drip Trig</title>
      <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/water-drip-trig/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/water-drip-trig/</guid>
      <description>Ellen Fullman demonstrating the Water Drip Drum, 1985 These are a few experiments I did in 2022 exploring the rhythmic qualities of dripping taps. I was inspired by the Water Drip Drum made by Ellen Fullman circa 1985. Her design involved a bucket filled with water with several different taps through which the water can drain. Depending on the tightness of the taps, the water drips onto other metal buckets below at certain rates, causing a resonant percussive sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assembly - Somerset House Studios</title>
      <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/assembly-2019-2020-somerset-house-studios/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/assembly-2019-2020-somerset-house-studios/</guid>
      <description>In 2019 and 2020 I was privileged to work with Somerset House Studios on their Assembly series showcasing contemporary electronic and experimental music.
A photo taken during the Assembly 2019 event A photo taken during the Assembly 2019 event In 2019, I collaborated with musicians and artists Beatrice Dillon, Haroon Mirza and, John Butcher &amp;amp; Lasse Marhaug for Somerset House Studios’ annual ASSEMBLY festival. I developed custom musical tools for each artist using Max/MSP, Wekinator and Touch OSC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Retoucher</title>
      <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/the-retoucher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/the-retoucher/</guid>
      <description>CLICK HERE TO LISTEN
The poster produced for the live recording of &amp;#39;The Retoucher&amp;#39; podcast In 2019, I co-developed and produced a science-fiction podcast for BBC Sounds titled The Retoucher in which I used sound as a central world building tool. I used experimental recording methods to rig a club venue with microphones which captured the actors and DJ’s performances in-situ over the course of an evening.
Binaural dummy head microphone recording ambiences in the smoking area behind the club.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>A selection of work that I have worked on over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
