<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tommie Introna: Sound Specialist, Creative Technologist &amp; Researcher</title>
    <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tommie Introna: Sound Specialist, Creative Technologist &amp; Researcher</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Water Drip Trig</title>
      <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/water-drip-trig/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/water-drip-trig/</guid>
      <description>These are a few experiments I did exploring the rhythmic qualities of dripping taps. I was inspired by the Water Drip Drum made by Ellen Fullman circa 1985. Her design involved a bucket filled with water with several different taps through which the water can drain. Depending on the tightness of the taps, the water drips onto other metal buckets below at certain rates, causing a resonant percussive sound. The concept is not too dissimilar to the Suikinkutsu &amp;ldquo;a type of Japanese garden ornament and music device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Womb of things to be and tomb of things that were</title>
      <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/womb-of-things-to-be-and-tomb-of-things-that-were/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 09:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/womb-of-things-to-be-and-tomb-of-things-that-were/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Womb of things to be and tomb of things that were&amp;rsquo; is a film by Charles Pryor and Marleen Boschen that explores collaborative survival, containment and vulnerability through seeds. Via episodic, speculative storytelling we follow seed banking and saving practices across the globe from the Millennium Seed Bank and the John Innes Centre in the UK, to a forest gene bank in Poland and a food sovereignty organisation in Palestine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on the lamenting voice</title>
      <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/reflection-on-the-lamenting-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 18:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/reflection-on-the-lamenting-voice/</guid>
      <description>Recently I watched a talk by Eleni Ikoniadou in which she presented her recent work Future Chrous. https://schedule.mozillafestival.org/session/QTHPSU-1
She discussed how in western thinking, speech is often taken as a marker of human inteligence. For Aristottle via Heidegger - man is a political speaking animal, a being who has a language which addresses and discusses its world. For the Greeks, voice without speech was considered irrational and dangerous associated with female, animal, disabled and non-human entities</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am not a Rubato</title>
      <link>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/i-am-not-a-rubato/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 12:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ttoommmmiiee.github.io/posts/i-am-not-a-rubato/</guid>
      <description>In 1997, artist and music producer Terre Thaemlitz released her album Die Roboter under the moniker Rubato. The album comprises piano interpretations of classic Kraftwerk titles. On first listen, the piano rendition sounds like a live performance by a talented and expressive pianist, playing a real piano with rich acoustic tones. The only sonic hint of manipulation is the noise that washes over the piano playing.
LISTEN: Die Roboter Rubato: Piano interpretations of Kraftwerk titles by Terre Thaemlitz</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
